<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>environmentalism on Shanduur&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://shanduur.github.io/tags/environmentalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in environmentalism on Shanduur&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shanduur.github.io/tags/environmentalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ballad of removed Charging Brick</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/5-ballad-of-removed-charger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/5-ballad-of-removed-charger/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, on October 13, Apple presented its new smartphones - iPhone 12 Mini, iPhone 12, iPhone 12 Pro, and iPhone 12 Pro Max. The Pro series was just a small incremental update over last year&amp;rsquo;s prosumer phones. Upgrade in the consumer series is quite significant - we now have a better screen, with a bigger DPI than the previous year&amp;rsquo;s iPhone 11. What shocked most of the people was information about removing the charging brick, due to reducing the amount of waste produced by the company every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The movie you should watch - A Life on Our Planet</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/2-life-on-our-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/2-life-on-our-planet/</guid>
      <description>I never talked about the natural environment in public. But the educational value of this movie is that big that I can&amp;rsquo;t just watch it and pass by without sharing it with anyone. Maybe some of you already watched David Attenborough: A Life on Our Planet recently added to Netflix. It tells a story about the natural environment, which surrounds us, and on which we have a devastating impact. Sir David Attenborough is a legendary narrator, traveler, and popularizer of natural science in the whole world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
