<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shanduur&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shanduur&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shanduur.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Broken Sapphire RX 480 Nitro</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/6-sapphire-rx-480/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/6-sapphire-rx-480/</guid>
      <description>So recently I laid my hands on this AMD Radeon RX 480. This is 4GB version from Sapphire, Nitro edition. Firstly I took a look on the PCB, cleaned it a little bit, removed solder from the place where someone accidentally removed one of capacitors, added some low quality thermal paste (Thermal Sliver AG).
Alpine I connected it via PCI-e riser to the test rig (AMD Athlon 64 x2 5200+ and Gigabyte GA-M57SLI-S4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ballad of removed Charging Brick</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/5-ballad-of-removed-charger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/5-ballad-of-removed-charger/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, on October 13, Apple presented its new smartphones - iPhone 12 Mini, iPhone 12, iPhone 12 Pro, and iPhone 12 Pro Max. The Pro series was just a small incremental update over last year&amp;rsquo;s prosumer phones. Upgrade in the consumer series is quite significant - we now have a better screen, with a bigger DPI than the previous year&amp;rsquo;s iPhone 11. What shocked most of the people was information about removing the charging brick, due to reducing the amount of waste produced by the company every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My remote development tools (part 3) - Virtual Network</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/4-remote-dev-3-virtual-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/4-remote-dev-3-virtual-net/</guid>
      <description>Last part of mine remote development kit, is virtual software defined network. I don&amp;rsquo;t have access to public IP, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t setup VPN. The solution was quite simple - virtual software defined network. My goal was to find something free or freemium and open source. Firstly I stumbled upon ZeroTier One and later I found Tailscale. Both seemed to fulfill my needs, so I will write something about both of them, although do not consider me as specialist - those will be only my thoughts on those pieces of software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My remote development tools (part 2) - Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/3-remote-dev-2-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/3-remote-dev-2-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Visual Studio Code is an Electron-based app with large community support. It was initially developed as a fork of Atom - an open-source code editor developed by GitHub. As it&amp;rsquo;s Electron-based, there is little overhead compared to other code editors like Sublime Text 3, Kate, or Notepad++. But its biggest strength is customizability. It supports a huge number of community developed plugins and themes. I will focus mostly on the ones used by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The movie you should watch - A Life on Our Planet</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/2-life-on-our-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/2-life-on-our-planet/</guid>
      <description>I never talked about the natural environment in public. But the educational value of this movie is that big that I can&amp;rsquo;t just watch it and pass by without sharing it with anyone. Maybe some of you already watched David Attenborough: A Life on Our Planet recently added to Netflix. It tells a story about the natural environment, which surrounds us, and on which we have a devastating impact. Sir David Attenborough is a legendary narrator, traveler, and popularizer of natural science in the whole world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My remote development tools (part 1) - Docker</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/1-remote-dev-1-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/1-remote-dev-1-docker/</guid>
      <description>As most of the programs that I am developing are CLI tools or servers, and they don&amp;rsquo;t feature any Graphical User Interface, I recently started my developing inside Docker containers. As I own some low power server, that is fast and stable enough to handle compiling software inside Docker, I decided that I will host this myself. In this miniseries, I will present how I created my setup, and I will explain why I did those things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello!</title>
      <link>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/0-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shanduur.github.io/posts/0-hello/</guid>
      <description>Good to see you there! I am a student at the Silesian University of Technology, at the time of writing this post, I&amp;rsquo;m during my final (7th) semester of Electronic, Control, and Information Engineering major. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m employed by Asseco Poland.
Interests? Many! Servers I love to work with the servers. My final thesis project is pluggabl - app for distributed image processing. I will share it&amp;rsquo;s code on GitHub when it&amp;rsquo;s finished, but until this moment, I can tell that it is using gRPC for Client / Server communication and it&amp;rsquo;s written in GoLang.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
